Hello, English learners, and welcome to another great podcast with EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎收听又一期精彩的EnglishPod播客。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erica.
我是Erica。
And today we have another really great lesson for you, elementary lesson.
今天我们为大家准备了另一节非常棒的课程，是一节初级课程。
That's right, and it's another lesson about money.
没错，而且又是一节关于钱的课程。
We have no money here at EnglishPod.
我们在EnglishPod可没钱。
We are in debt here.
我们负债累累。
In debt.
负债。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好吧。
In debt.
负债。
So, what does that mean?
那是什么意思呢？
Why don't you tell us?
不如你来告诉我们？
If I owe you money, I'm in debt.
如果我欠你钱，我就负债了。
In fact, I think I am in debt to you.
事实上，我觉得我欠你钱。
You owe me $2.50 for a Coke Zero today.
你今天欠我2.5美元买零度可乐。
That's true.
没错。
All right.
好吧。
Okay, so let's get started.
好了，我们开始吧。
Let's take a look at our vocabulary preview.
我们先来看一下词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
We have two words today in our vocabulary preview, and the first one is recession.
今天的词汇预览中有两个词，第一个是recession。
Recession.
经济衰退。
So, recession.
所以，经济衰退。
Everyone's talking about it right now, and what does it mean?
现在每个人都在谈论它，它是什么意思呢？
I don't know.
我不知道。
That's your job.
那是你的工作。
I don't know.
我不知道。
I really don't know.
我真的不知道。
Why don't you tell me, Erica, because this isn't my topic for today.
不如你来告诉我吧，Erica，因为这不是我今天的话题。
Okay.
好吧。
Recession is a period of time when the economy of a country is doing badly.
经济衰退是指一个国家经济表现不佳的一段时间。
In a recession, the country is making less money.
在经济衰退中，国家赚的钱更少。
That's true.
没错。
Maybe we can give a few examples of things that happen in a recession to show the meaning
也许我们可以举几个经济衰退中发生的事情的例子，来更好地说明
of this a little bit better.
这个词的意思。
Right.
对。
So, for example, in a recession, many people lose their jobs.
比如，在经济衰退中，很多人会失业。
Because companies might close or go bankrupt.
因为公司可能会倒闭或破产。
Exactly.
没错。
And also, people start spending less money.
而且，人们开始减少开支。
That's true.
确实如此。
And the stock prices of companies fall.
公司的股价也会下跌。
Pretty dramatic.
相当严重。
Yeah, they fall a lot, hey?
是啊，跌得很厉害，对吧？
Yeah.
对。
That's what's going on now in the United States.
这就是美国现在的情况。
Very true.
非常正确。
Okay.
好的。
So, let's take a look at our second word, and it has to do with recession.
那么，我们来看看第二个词，它和经济衰退有关。
It's broke.
身无分文。
Broke.
I'm broke.
我身无分文。
Broke.
身无分文。
It means that you have no money.
意思是你没有钱。
You're broke.
你身无分文。
I'm broke.
我身无分文。
Right.
对。
So, these are our two words for vocabulary preview today, and you're going to hear them
这就是今天词汇预览的两个词，你会在对话中听到它们。
in the dialogue.
在对话中。
This dialogue is about a man who is in debt.
这段对话是关于一个负债累累的男人。
He's broke.
他身无分文。
Let's find out what happens.
我们来看看发生了什么。
Hello.
你好。
I'm here to see Mr. Corleone.
我来见柯里昂先生。
Right this way, sir.
这边请，先生。
Charlie, what can I do for you?
查理，我能为你做些什么？
Mr. Corleone, I'm really sorry to trouble you, but I need your help.
柯里昂先生，很抱歉打扰您，但我需要您的帮助。
Anything for you, Charlie.
查理，为你做什么都行。
Your father was like a brother to me.
你父亲就像我的兄弟一样。
Well, sir, you see, this recession has hit me pretty hard.
嗯，先生，您看，这次经济衰退对我打击很大。
I lost my job, and I'm in a lot of debt.
我丢了工作，欠了很多债。
I see.
我明白了。
Yeah, you know, I've got credit card bills, car payments, I've got to pay my mortgage,
是啊，您知道，我有信用卡账单、车贷，还要还房贷，
and on top of all that, I have to pay my son's college tuition.
除此之外，我还要支付儿子的大学学费。
So you're asking for a loan.
所以你是来借钱的。
Well, I just thought maybe you could help me out.
嗯，我只是想也许您能帮我一把。
What?
什么？
At a time like this?
在这种时候？
I'm broke too, you know.
我也破产了，你知道吗。
You're not the only one who's been hit by the recession.
你不是唯一一个受经济衰退影响的人。
I lost half my money in the stock market crash.
我在股市崩盘中损失了一半的钱。
Go on.
继续。
Get out of here.
出去。
Okay, so that was a bit unexpected.
好吧，这有点出乎意料。
Yeah, that was certainly strange.
是啊，确实很奇怪。
He didn't go to the bank to ask for money, did he?
他不是去银行要钱的，对吧？
No, he went to the mob, and the mob is broke.
不，他去找了黑帮，而黑帮也破产了。
Oh no, you know it's a bad recession when even the mob runs out of money.
哦不，连黑帮都没钱了，你就知道经济衰退有多严重了。
All right, so why don't we start by looking at our language takeaway.
好的，那我们先从今天的语言要点开始吧。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
All right, so for today's language takeaway, we have four words from the dialogue which
好的，今天的语言要点，我们有四个来自对话的单词，
we think are really important.
我们认为它们非常重要。
Yes, so why don't we start with the first one?
是的，那我们先从第一个开始吧？
Loan.
贷款。
So, Erika, tell us about a loan.
那么，Erika，给我们讲讲贷款。
What is a loan?
什么是贷款？
Okay, when you borrow money, you get a loan.
好的，当你借钱时，你就获得了一笔贷款。
A loan, yes.
贷款，是的。
Not to be confused with alone, like by myself.
不要和“独自”混淆，比如我一个人。
No, so this is L-O-A-N.
不，这个是L-O-A-N。
Loan.
贷款。
Right.
对。
Okay, great.
好的，很好。
Let's take a look at our second word, mortgage.
我们来看第二个词，抵押贷款。
Mortgage.
抵押贷款。
Now, this is very common.
这个很常见。
I'm sure many of you have mortgages.
我相信你们很多人都有抵押贷款。
What is a mortgage?
什么是抵押贷款？
A mortgage is a type of a loan.
抵押贷款是一种贷款。
Basically, it's a loan that helps you to buy a house.
基本上，它是一种帮助你买房的贷款。
A house or a property.
房子或房产。
Yeah, so this is a funny word.
是啊，这个词挺有意思的。
I mean, there's this strange mortgage with a T.
我是说，有个奇怪的词 mortgage 带个 T。
Yeah, it has a T in it, but you don't pronounce it.
对，它里面有个 T，但不发音。
You say mortgage.
你读作 mortgage。
Mortgage.
Mortgage。
So not mortgage.
所以不是 mortgage。
Not mortgage.
不是 mortgage。
Mortgage.
Mortgage。
Mortgage, yeah.
Mortgage，对。
I had trouble spelling that one for this lesson, so I learned it well now.
这节课我拼这个词费了好大劲，现在总算记住了。
Okay.
好的。
Let's move to our third word today.
我们来看今天的第三个词。
Hit me pretty hard.
对我打击很大。
I think we have some examples that will help us understand this phrase.
我想有些例子能帮我们理解这个短语。
Example one.
例子一。
My divorce hit me pretty hard.
离婚对我打击很大。
I'm so depressed.
我很难过。
Example two.
例子二。
This cold has hit me pretty hard.
这次感冒让我病得不轻。
I've been in bed for a week.
我卧床一周了。
Example three.
例子三。
The news of Fluffy's death hit me pretty hard.
Fluffy 去世的消息对我打击很大。
I've been crying for days.
我哭了好几天。
Okay, so that's a lot clearer.
好的，这下清楚多了。
Yeah.
嗯。
Great.
太好了。
Why don't we take a look at our last word for language takeaway?
我们来看看语言要点部分的最后一个词。
Tuition.
学费。
So this is the money you have to pay to your school so that you can study there.
这是你为了上学而付给学校的钱。
Right.
对。
Usually, it's in college, right, or university.
通常是在大学，对吧？或者学院。
Yeah, but sometimes in some countries, you have to pay tuition for public school.
是的，但有些国家上公立学校也要付学费。
Okay, great.
好的，很好。
So it's time to listen to our dialogue again, and it's going to be slower so we can listen
现在我们来听一遍对话，这次会慢一些，方便我们听清。
to all the words that we just talked about.
对我们刚才讨论的所有单词。
Hello.
你好。
I'm here to see Mr. Corleone.
我来见柯里昂先生。
Right this way, sir.
这边请，先生。
Charlie, what can I do for you?
查理，我能为你做些什么？
Mr. Corleone, I'm really sorry to trouble you, but I need your help.
柯里昂先生，很抱歉打扰您，但我需要您的帮助。
Anything for you, Charlie.
为你做什么都行，查理。
Your father was like a brother to me.
你父亲就像我的兄弟一样。
Well, sir, you see, this recession has hit me pretty hard.
嗯，先生，您看，这次经济衰退对我打击很大。
I lost my job, and I'm in a lot of debt.
我丢了工作，还欠了很多债。
I see.
我明白了。
Yeah.
是的。
You know, I've got credit card bills, car payments, I've got to pay my mortgage, and
你知道，我有信用卡账单、车贷，还要还房贷，而且
on top of all that, I have to pay my son's college tuition.
除此之外，我还要支付儿子的大学学费。
So you're asking for a loan.
所以你是来借钱的。
Well, I just thought maybe you could help me out.
嗯，我只是想也许你能帮我一把。
What?
什么？
At a time like this?
在这种时候？
I'm broke too, you know.
我也破产了，你知道吗。
You're not the only one who has been hit by the recession.
你不是唯一一个受经济衰退影响的人。
I lost half my money in the stock market crash.
我在股市崩盘中损失了一半的钱。
Go on, get out of here.
走吧，离开这里。
Okay, so I think a lot of the key language we just talked about is a lot more clear now.
好了，我想我们刚才讨论的很多关键语言现在都更清楚了。
But you know, I also noticed some really interesting phrases in this dialogue.
但你知道吗，我还注意到这段对话中有一些非常有趣的短语。
Yes, I did too.
是的，我也注意到了。
So let's start with Fluency Builder.
那么我们从流利度构建器开始吧。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
Fluency Builder is a tool that we use to help you sound more native.
流利度构建器是一个工具，用来帮助你说话更像母语者。
Right, so you can sound more natural when you're speaking.
对，这样你说话时就能更自然。
So we take a really common phrase, and we show you some great natural ways of expressing
所以我们选取一个非常常见的短语，然后向你展示一些表达同样意思的非常自然的方式。
that same idea.
表达同样的意思。
Exactly.
没错。
And today we have three of these examples.
今天我们有三个这样的例子。
Let's start with the first one.
让我们从第一个开始。
So this phrase we use when we want to ask somebody, can I help you?
这个短语用于当我们想问某人“我能帮你吗？”的时候。
What can I do for you?
我能为你做些什么？
Yeah, that sounds really, really polite and really natural.
是的，这听起来非常非常礼貌，也非常自然。
Right, so instead of saying, can I help you?
对，所以与其说“我能帮你吗？”
Or, I don't know, what do you need?
或者，我不知道，“你需要什么？”
We can just say, what can I do for you?
我们只需说，我能为你做什么？
Exactly.
没错。
So let's move to our second phrase.
那我们来看第二个短语。
This phrase we use when we need something, when we want to say, I'm sorry to bother you.
这个短语在我们需要某物时使用，当我们想说，抱歉打扰你。
Or, I'm sorry to interrupt.
或者，抱歉打断一下。
Okay, let's listen.
好的，我们来听一下。
I'm really sorry to trouble you.
真的很抱歉麻烦你。
I'm sorry to trouble you.
抱歉麻烦你。
This phrase might be a little bit more difficult to understand how it's used, but we've got
这个短语可能有点难理解如何使用，但我们有
some examples.
一些例子。
Yes, so let's listen.
是的，我们来听一下。
Example one.
例子一。
Can I trouble you for a moment?
能麻烦你一下吗？
I just need you to sign this form for me.
我只需要你帮我签这份表格。
Example two.
例子二。
I'm sorry to trouble you, but may I go home early today?
抱歉麻烦你，但我今天能早点回家吗？
Example three.
例子三。
Can I trouble you for a pen?
能麻烦你借我一支笔吗？
Mine is not working anymore.
我的笔不能用了。
Okay, so now let's take a look at our last phrase for fluency builder.
好的，现在我们来看流利度训练中的最后一个短语。
On top of all that.
更糟糕的是。
This is a really useful phrase.
这是一个非常有用的短语。
Marco, how would you use it?
Marco，你会怎么用它？
Well, for example, today I lost my job.
嗯，例如，今天我丢了工作。
Oh no.
哦不。
My car got stolen.
我的车被偷了。
Oh my God.
哦天哪。
And on top of all that, my girlfriend broke up with me.
更糟糕的是，我女朋友和我分手了。
That was a terrible day.
那是糟糕的一天。
It was, but don't worry.
是的，但别担心。
You can use this phrase also in a positive way.
你也可以用这个短语表达积极的意思。
That's true.
没错。
You could say, so today was a really great day.
你可以说，今天真是很棒的一天。
It was my birthday and all my friends came to visit me and on top of all that, I got
今天是我的生日，所有的朋友都来看我，更棒的是，我收到了
a million presents.
一百万个礼物。
That is a great day.
那真是美好的一天。
So you can use on top of all that in this way.
所以你可以这样使用“更糟糕的是”这个短语。
Just like and also.
就像，还有。
And also, yeah.
还有，是的。
Yeah.
是的。
So on top of all that.
除此之外。
So we are ready to listen to our dialogue a third time.
所以我们准备第三次听对话。
We can hear all the words that we just talked about and all the phrases and you'll definitely
我们可以听到我们刚刚讨论的所有单词和短语，你肯定
be able to understand a lot better now.
现在能更好地理解了。
Hello.
你好。
I'm here to see Mr. Corleone.
我来见柯里昂先生。
This way, sir.
这边请，先生。
Charlie, what can I do for you?
查理，我能为你做些什么？
Mr. Corleone, I'm really sorry to trouble you, but I need your help.
柯里昂先生，很抱歉打扰您，但我需要您的帮助。
Anything for you, Charlie.
为你做什么都行，查理。
Your father was like a brother to me.
你父亲就像我的兄弟一样。
Well, sir, you see, this recession has hit me pretty hard.
嗯，先生，您看，这次经济衰退对我打击很大。
I lost my job and I'm in a lot of debt.
我丢了工作，还欠了很多债。
I see.
我明白了。
Yeah, you know, I've got credit card bills, car payments.
是的，你知道，我有信用卡账单、车贷。
I've got to pay my mortgage.
我还要付房贷。
And on top of all that, I have to pay my son's college tuition.
除此之外，我还要支付儿子的大学学费。
So you're asking for a loan.
所以你是来借钱的。
Well, I just thought maybe you could help me out.
嗯，我只是想也许你能帮我一把。
What?
什么？
At a time like this?
在这种时候？
I'm broke too, you know.
我也破产了，你知道吗。
You're not the only one who's been hit by the recession.
你不是唯一一个受经济衰退影响的人。
I lost half my money in the stock market crash.
我在股市崩盘中损失了一半的钱。
Go on.
继续。
I'm out of here.
我走了。
Today's dialogue was all about being in debt, right?
今天的对话都是关于负债的，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
And, and different people have different attitudes or different viewpoints on being in debt.
而且，不同的人对负债有不同的态度或观点。
Yes, that's true.
是的，没错。
For example, in North America and in Canada, it's a really common thing.
例如，在北美和加拿大，这是很常见的事。
Yeah, it's actually almost good to be in debt.
是的，实际上负债几乎是好事。
It's more than good.
不仅仅是好事。
It's necessary to be in debt.
负债是必要的。
That's right.
没错。
Unless you have a history of being in debt and regularly paying off your debts, you can't
除非你有负债并定期还清债务的记录，否则你实际上无法
actually borrow money.
借到钱。
You can't get a mortgage.
你无法获得抵押贷款。
You can't get a car loan so you can buy a new car.
你无法获得购车贷款来买新车。
Right.
对。
That's called a credit history.
那叫做信用记录。
So you must have a good credit history in order to be able to, like you say, buy a car
所以你必须要有良好的信用记录，才能像你说的那样，买车
or buy a house.
或者买房。
Yeah.
是的。
And you know, the funny thing is, when I was in university, maybe I was 18 years old, the
而且你知道吗，有趣的是，我上大学的时候，大概18岁，
first thing that happened at university was, you know, banks came to our university and
大学里发生的第一件事就是，银行来到我们学校，
started offering you credit cards.
开始向你提供信用卡。
So you can get a credit card when you're 18, no problem.
所以你18岁就能拿到信用卡，没问题。
And not only do they offer you credit cards, they give you like free gifts if you sign
他们不仅提供信用卡，如果你申请信用卡，他们还会送你免费礼物。
up for a credit card.
So they really want you to have a credit card.
所以他们真的很想让你拥有信用卡。
Of course, they want you to spend more money.
当然，他们想让你花更多的钱。
That's the trick.
这就是套路。
Yeah.
是的。
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
It's totally different in Europe, for example.
例如在欧洲，情况完全不同。
I used to live in Switzerland and there, they're really careful with debt.
我以前住在瑞士，那里的人对债务非常谨慎。
Like it's a bad thing to be in debt.
欠债是一件坏事。
Well, yeah.
嗯，是的。
I mean, it's bad to be in debt.
我的意思是，欠债是不好的。
Definitely.
当然。
For example, if I want to have a credit card in Switzerland and let's say I want to have
例如，如果我想在瑞士有一张信用卡，假设我想
a limit of 500 francs that I can spend every month.
每月有500法郎的额度可以花。
I need to put in my bank account 700 francs before I can even spend that credit card money.
我需要在我的银行账户里存入700法郎，然后才能使用信用卡里的钱。
So it's totally opposite from North America.
所以这与北美完全相反。
Well, yeah.
嗯，是的。
I mean, in North America, it's crazy the way that people are in debt and it's showing now
我的意思是，在北美，人们负债的方式很疯狂，现在经济衰退就体现出来了，对吧？
with the recession, right?
Yeah, that's true.
是的，没错。
So everyone, be sure to handle your money carefully.
所以大家，一定要谨慎理财。
Don't be in debt unless you really, really have to.
除非万不得已，不要负债。
Good financial advice from EnglishPod.
来自EnglishPod的理财建议。
EnglishPod financial advising service.
EnglishPod理财咨询服务。
Okay, everyone.
好了，各位。
Thanks for listening.
感谢收听。
Now, remember, if you have any questions or comments, please visit our website at EnglishPod.com.
现在，请记住，如果你有任何问题或评论，请访问我们的网站EnglishPod.com。
Right.
对。
Erika and I are always there to answer all the questions and we really like to receive
我和Erika随时都在这里回答所有问题，我们非常喜欢收到
comments and suggestions from all our users.
来自所有用户的评论和建议。
So be sure to go and leave us your comments.
所以一定要去给我们留言哦。
Okay, Marco.
好的，Marco。
It's been fun.
今天很开心。
Yes, it has.
是的，很开心。
But sadly, we have to go now.
但遗憾的是，我们现在得走了。
So until next time, it's...
那么下次再见，这里是……
Goodbye.
再见。